Asgard
Wotan
Lyran Commonwealth
22 March 2990

"So who the dreck Is Georg Suertos?" Durant Carlyle wanted to know. "I know he's a local fat cat—"
    "'Fat cat' doesn't even begin to cover it, Captain," Major Jonathan Colby replied, shifting the ever-present cigar stub to the other side of his mouth. "Not by about ten thousand light years. He's probably the richest guy on Wotan."
    "And he wants us, huh?"
    "Yuppers," Colby replied. "At least...he wants a couple battle lances of medium to heavy BattleMechs. And on Wotan, that's pretty much the same thing."
    They'd been making their way through the more unsavory part of town. Asgard was large, bright, and modern as near-Periphery worlds went, but it WAS near-Periphery, and a bit on the old-fashioned side. The Asgard Citadel loomed over the city from atop the mountain, but the streets in its deepest shadows tended to be narrow, crowded, and loud. Colby led the way, consulting a torn slip of paper several times before stopping and pointing at a garish facade.
    "What," Carlyle said, surprised. "In there?"
    "The World Tree," Colby replied. "That's the place."
    "I would have thought someone as rich as this guy would have better taste in hangouts."
    "Actually, he owns the Joint," Colby replied. "And I never question how a client chooses to spend his free time."
    The World Tree was crowded, loud, and, shrouded in smoky near-darkness. Two young women writhed and gyrated on a small       stage-in-the-round to the thumpa-thumpa-thumpa of something that might have been a canned version of "Hard Man" by the Blackstarz. A few people danced where they could find room on the floor; most of the joint's patrons hunched over too-expencive drinks or stared at the dancers.
    "What'll it be, guys?" a hostess asked. She was pretty but either tiredness or boredom had ground off the bright edges.
    "We're here to see Suartos," Colby told her. He made a fiver materialize between his fingers. "Colby. He's expecting us."
    The woman made the C-bill vanish, though Carlyle couldn't tell where it had gone. She wasn't wearing much, and definitely was short on pockets. "Over there," she said, pointing to an empty booth with her chin. "I'll tell him."
    They threaded through the chaos and took the indicated table. A reserved light glowed above the shabby surface.
    "So...do you have any idea at all what the job is?" Carlyle asked his C.O. He punched in the code for a beer on the tabletop's order pad. Colby did the same.
    "Nope. Off-world is all l know. And he wants a two-lance contract."
    "Well, were almost there," Carlyle said. Second Lance was short a 'Mech—Pryor's Thunderbolt had blown a coolant seal and fried a couple primary actuators.
    Their drinks arrived a few moments later, followed soon after by a beefy men in sharply tailored utilities. "Reid," he growled by way of introduction. Carlyle didn't like his looks...hard and dark and...just a bit slimy. "You Colby?"
    "I have business with Suartos," Colby said.
    "I work for Mister Suartos," Reid said. "He has a job for you, if the price is right."
    "What kind of job?"
    "Vermin control. He wants you to put the kibosh on a little invasion."
    Carlyle watched Colby sizing the man up. "I see. Maybe you'd better fill us in."
    Reid pulled out a small holoprojector disk and placed it on the table. It was an expensive little gadget, the sort of technology you rarely saw nowadays. Data appeared in the air above it, along with the ghostly image of a planet.
    Just a hair over nineteen light years from Wotan was an arid eyeball world by the name of Golandrinas. The innermost of an M7 red dwarf. Goiandrinas was tidally locked to its primary, one hemisphere forever baking beneath the sullen, blood-hued sun, the night side capped by ice. The planetary capital of Rowe was located in the twilight zone, the narrow band circling the ugly little world where the sun gently and continually rose and fell above the same horizon with the planet's slow librations. Fierce winds and heat storms driven by solar heating kept the temperatures around the terminator more or less bearable; only in the Deep Night was it so cold that a circular ice cape had formed, creating the glassy blind pupil of what looked like an enormous eyeball staring out into the darkness beyond its sun.
    "Trent is the infected pimple on the planet's ass," Reid told them. A point of light marked Its location six hundred kilometers from Rowe, well into the world's night half. "It's not part of the local government. It's ruled by a local petty warlord by the name of Duboise."
    A man's image replaced the planet hanging above the table. Scar tissue and an eye patch beneath a hairless scalp suggested he'd been through a few wars.
    "Former Arcturian Guards," Reid told them. "Mean son-of-a-bitch. Uses raw terror to keep the peasants in line. He's been hiring mercs, mostly from the Periphery—in particular some scum called the Deathgeld. The word is he's going to march on Rowe."
    "Local forces?" Colby asked. "Planetary militia? Auxiliaries?"
    "Nothing worth mentioning." Reid hesitated. "There's...not a lot on the planet of any value."
    "Realty? Then why is Mater Suartos interested in the place?"
    "Maybe," Carlyle said. speaking for the first time, "it has to do with Vickers Mining."
    Reid gave him a sour look that told Carlyle he'd just hit it on the head.
    Vickers was a major mining company for the entire district, with its headquarters located on Derf, less than eighteen light years from Wotan. It had operations on perhaps forty planets, moons, and asteroids throughout the region, with an emphasis on rare earths and minerals. Carlyle had seen a recent news item to the effect that the company's stock had just taken a big upward jump...something about rumors of a major mineral strike on one of their holdings. On Golandrinas, perhaps?
    "Is that true, Reid?" Colby asked the man. He chuckled. "Is Suarfos trying to protect his investment?"
    "That's not your business, Colby. Look, I can offer you half a million C-bills if you can disrupt Duboise's Golandrinas operation...plus one hundred thousand per 'Mech."
    "Uh-uh," Colby said, shaking his head. "One minion plus twenty. And you pay the transport."
    "Eight hundred thousand, plus one-ten...and transport."
    "Done."

Union-class Dropship Ragamuffin
Golandrinas
Lyran Commonwealth
5 April 2990

Carlyle drifted in the common room of the Ragamuffin, falling down the long and steepening slope of the local gravity well toward the night side of Golandrinas. Through the observation cupola, he could just make out the eyeball world ahead, illuminated by starlight and peering up at the DropShip from the dark. The local sun was in eclipse, but the planet was edged by a bright red partial halo refracted through atmosphere.
    "Your C.O. wants us to put down right outside of Trent,' the ship's skipper told him. Hank Austin looked at least as old as his venerable vessel. With those weathered wrinkles and that white beard, he would have been right at home on the deck of a Terran sailing ship from twelve hundred years ago. "He got pretty testy when I suggested a landing area farther out horn town."
    "Well, he always gets a bit short-tempered when he can't smoke," Carlyle said, grinning. Colby's Commandos had engaged the Ragamuffin more than once before. Austin and his ship were frequent sights throughout the region, from Tamar to the Periphery.
    "Hey, the ventilation systems on these old Unions ain't all that good," Austin said with a shrug. "You want to breathe, you keep the pollutants down."
    "Not a problem, Captain. By the time we hit dirt, hell be cranky enough to bite the head off a Shadow Hawk."
    "So, I gather this is just a quick in-and-out?" Austin asked.
    "Right. According to our intel, there's a 'Mech park at the edge of the town, a kind of headquarters for Duboise's thugs. If we can pop in on them before they saddle up, we can shoot up their 'Mechs and be outbound again before they know what hit them."
    "What intel?"
    "Suartos's man gave us a dossier that thick," Carlyle said, holding up a thumb and forefinger stretched apart to show a massive tome. "And the C.O. used that to put us together a pretty good plan. Maximum destruction for a minimum of risk."
    "Huh."
    "What's 'huh'?"
    "Nothin'. It's just that in my experience, the very best military plans, based on the very best military intelligence, tend to be the ones that go pear-shaped in the biggest hurry."
    Carlyle laughed. "Don't worry! The intel isn't that good...."
    "What I can't figure," Austin said, scratching his beard, "is what the bet a rich bastard like Suartos thinks two lances can do against an operation like Duboise."
    "Damfino," Carlyle said with a shrug. "I figure it's because of the Golden Rule."
    "Golden Rule?"
    "Sure. You know 'the man with the gold makes the rules.'"

▲▼▲

An hour later, Carlyle stood on the Second Lance 'Mech bay. The Ragamuffin was under one G of thrust now, banishing freefall and replacing it with the sensation of weight. The ship was backing down toward the planet's night side with a shuddering growl that rattled her bulkheads and sent vibrations rippling through the steel deck gratings.
    Carlyle had gathered with the other members of his lance and the Commandos tech ream. They were fifteen minutes out from grounding; time to saddle up and jack in. The lance 'Mechs towered around them in the deep and looming shadows.
    Pryor's 'Mech was still out of action, though they'd brought it along to continue the repair, strapped immobile within its gantry. De Salva's Commando, Bryant's Catapult, and Carlyle's own Shadow Hawk brooded to the right of the partially disassembled Thunderbolt, with most of the gantry walks and accessways already cleared away. The three of them had stripped down to shorts and were strapping on their coolant vests.
    De Salva whistled as Natalie Bryant's olive green tank-top rode up a bit. "Nice. babe!"
    "Hey!" Carlyle barked in his best none-of-that parade-ground bellow. "Can it, Diesel!"
    "Blake's Blood! You can't blame a guy for looking!" De Salva said, leering.
    "Never mind. Durant," Natalie told him. "Poor guy hasn't had any action for so long, all he can do is look!"
    De Salva's face went dark. "Screw you!"
    "Ooh..." Bryant said,. cinching her vest closed with a dramatic flourish and sealing it. "Don't you just wish!"
    "Both of you knock it of!" Carlyle snapped. As Executive Officer of Colby's Commandos and the skipper of the Second Lance, it was up to him to keep his unit functioning smoothly and with a minimum of interpersonal issues. De Salva and Bryant were always throwing barbs at one another...but things had taken a nasty turn lately without David Pryor's mellow. levelling influence.
    Every one of them, he reflected, was stressing out over this contract. The trouble was that they did not, in fact, have good intel for this op, despite what Captain Austin had said earlier. The dossier Carlyle had mentioned was long on descriptions of the planet and its population, but frustradngly short on details of Duboise or his mercenary unit. Most merc units out here had a rep, but the warlord and his unit, a 'Mech company identified only as the Deathgeld, were both completely unknown.
    Maybe It was a brand-new unit Carlyle could only hope so. A 
  new unit meant that even If all or most of the MechWanlors were 
experienced, they weren't used to working together, as a team. 
    He looked at Bryant and be Salve and wondered If he was 
going to have the same problem.
    Deathgeld. What the hell did that even mean? Geld, as In 
'gelding," with the suggestion that they were out to castrate 
Death? Ora mispronunciation, deliberate or otherwise, of -guild; 
as In a death guild?
    Carlyle had no idea, and there didn't seem to be any Information 
out there on a merc unit by that name. Add Reld's secretiveness 
concerning Vickers Mining and his boss's connection to mysterious 
mineral strikes on GolandrInas. and Colby's Commandos were 
practically flying Into this op blind.

਍﻿   And mat sort of ignorance was men more nerve wracking for 
  company X.O. Man having members of his unit at one anoMers 
 throats.
   'Let's mount up. peoplef fie order,
   Cadyle, Shadow Hauck was two centuries old. but meticu- 
 lously and lovingly maintained. Massing Ilhy-five ton, stand- 
 ing nine meters high. Its primary armament was an Armstrong 
 p I autocannon mounted on its left shoulder. It tended to have 
 a problem with heat build-up, especially when using Its Martell 
 laser and lump fet, but this op. at least. shouldn't be much of a 
 problem. Ground temperatures at the landing zone stood at mi- 
 nus twenty Celsius. Things would have been a lot more dodgy if 
 mey'd had to fight on Golandrinas, day side.
  He rode the gantry lift to the access hatch, where Sergeant 
 gal Griffin was unsealing the cockpit hatch. 'You're ready to rock. 
 sir: Griffin told him.
  'Outstanding. Grid.' Using the grab bar. he slid In legs first, 
 ducking his head to clear the combing.
  'Dona  Captain,' Griffin told him. 'You owe me a C."
  "Id pay you when I get back" It was an ancient routine, a 
 means of staving off the looming fear. He had to come back If he 
 owed his crew chief money...at lemt that was the idea.
  Griffin cycled the hatch shut, then slapped it hard with his 
palm. to get the bastards. bossr
  Het. these feds probably didn't know who the Commandos 
would be fighting today. They kept it simple: get out of here and kW 
the bastards-
  Carlyle's neurohelmet was In Its rack above the seat. He lifted 
It then settled it down Over his head. the padding nestling against 
his shoulders. Once upon a time. some techs whispered. It had 
been possible to run a dffideMech entirely through thoughts 
transmitted through the helmet Carlyle wasn't sure he believed 
them. however. This neurohelmet was a far simpler and more 
primitive affair. feeding the MechWarrlor with cues through his 
inner ears concerning balance and attitude.
 After going through the voice recognition and engine start- 
up sequences, he engaged the power, and felt the 'Meth come 
to life around him: no longer a massive, vaguely humanoid 
tower of articulated metal, but an extension of his body. Views- 
creens on his console showed Griffin and several other astechs 
scrambling clear.

਍﻿        -r           to touchdown: Austin's voice said over Carlyle'. 
       amm system. "LaerunadY strop                     •
        Hose 6sr couple or minutes were aMaYs ris         toscs,
        me shuddering ho wi of the Ragamuffin's Fu 
     increased in pitch and volume...and Men Cariyie felt the bump 
     as the propShips massive pads kissed the ground. Aral.. he 
     thought. is good. The Commandos had used his urvIces on 
     several ops before this one. and M never disappointed.
        lust so he was still around when it came time to dust off.
        The enormous cargo deck hatches cycled open on darkness. 
     and the magnetic grapples hoiding Carlyle's Shadow Hausa upright 
     In Its gantry released their grip. Carlyle pressed his throttle pedal 
     and the 'Meth stepped forward; the steel deck flexing. ever so 
     slightly, beneath his foot "Let's go. people
       He strode down the ramp and into the pool of radiance 
     horn the ship's landing lights. as the Salve's Commando and 
     Bryant's Catapult followed. Carlyle's external sensors registered 
   minus eighteen Celsius, and as he cleared the lee of the ship 
   the wind struck him full-force, howling In at ninety kilometers 
   per hour.
       The ground was bare and rocky. They'd landed well clear of 
  the nIghtside Ice sheet, but frozen pellets rattled incessantly off 
  his cockpit in the shrieking gale. The sky overhead was black with 
  tumbling cloud wrack. As he stepped out of the light around the ship 
  and into the encircling darkness. a lagged horizon showed in one 
  direction. a red-orange streak of sky...a dawn that never came.
     Other 'Meths moved clear of the DropShip, silhouetted by the 
  glare of the lights—First Lance. with Hauptman's Shadow Hawk, 
  Zeller's and Hernandeb's Locusts, and Colby's 6M Wolverine.
             PlanAlpha," Colby ordered. 'Carlyle?Houptman? You're

     The company's two Shadow Hawks were generally tasked with 
  recon. "Roger that: Carlyle said.
     The Shadow Hawk was Durant Carlyle's favorite 'Mech, 
  a near-perfect fusion of maneuverability and firepower. Its 
  maneuverability was in large part due to the three Pltban LFT- 
50 jump jets mounted In its torso, with a combined thrust that 
could boost the machine up to ninety meters In the proverbial 
single bound. Carlyle engaged his jets and held them for the 
maximum burn time. sailing In a low, fast arc across the dark 
landscape.

਍﻿The howiing gale clawed at his 'ree:h.buthpen..hddeldi.omtead,dy.  
sixty meters to his left Lieutenant Earns,st d	
rd...dmn;
Lance. piloted the company's second	
°
rete's 'Ugh, his jump lets flaring brightly in tame C' So much. Cads. thought Jor vrn.g.°4
But It couldn't be helped and the enemy would hdkovdwbd:
coming by	
anyway 'n" ffiel';y":1bZ touchdown 
kln8 the on radar. They'd allowed for that in the battle plan, 
Ragamuffin's "'rc'acb.with the  
DropShip deliberately touching down just two kilometers from  
the objective.
That objective was a BattleMech staging depot, the reported 
home bas° of the mercenary unit Me warlord Dubmse w
e'n	
as
s assault on	
. the ramshackle town of Trent

half rkitr bom' kilometer further on and a bit to the south. Plan A was  
as brutally simple and direct hit the depot, knock down the wall,  
and shoot up Me 'Meths Inside before they could be manned and  
scrambled. Another lump should duY...
Carlyle came down on rocky ground just outside the depot  
wall. The gate was several hundred meters to the left, but he  
preferred a more direct route, from a range of thirty meters, he  
opened up with his autocannon, the heavy siren-skim-slam of  
annor-piercIng high explosive shells punching deep Into prefab  
ferrocrere slab, lighting up the night with cackling, pulsing  
detonations. Hauptman touched down nearby and added his  
autorennon's fury to the storm. Bits and pieces of shattering wall  
pinged and linked off Carlyle's armor.
The wall was lust ten meters tail: the two Shadow Hawks could  
easily have leaped over It with a brief burn of their jump jets, but  
the Idea was to open a hole for the rest of the company, which  
would be coming up from behind very soon now. Intended more  
to deter foot infantry than 'Mechs, the wall crumbled and sagged  
In billowing clouds of ferrocrete dust swiftly whipped away by the  
blistering cold wind.
'Commandos, Recon." he called over his comm unit. 'We  
have a breach
"Goodgoing. Peron," Colby's voice replied. "We'rea fere mimeMs  
behind you."
Carlyle scanned the Interior of the depot fortress through  
the gap in the wall with IR. and pinked up the fast-moving red  
and yellow Images of running men against the cooler blues and  
violets of the background.

਍﻿and triggered his lump lets hobnob,  
Me	
reach and coming down in front of the 
ocv Me rubbie of Ina b
facnity's Mach ganMes
gave him Pause.
Wha"esrn	
'Li rad of twelve scaffolding towers
me	
'ide and fifteen rnmers high. with
meshed together.side by:..‘mning in every direction. There
power ve"1-teMechs there. the objective Corers
should have	
damage or destroy...but there
Commandos had been r'aid to damage	
WM111brooff and a
re lust two within MM.. storage slots. a
35-ton Pant.,
called -We've got problem,  
-Command, Itecon: Gayle	
.
WS, Ulf,
"Two Mechs In their slots Space In the racks for ten more, hot
they're all empty. I think they've flown the coop:
conversation was abruptly Interrupted by a stream of  
heavy machine chine gun rounds clanging and rattling off the side of  
Carlyle 's 'Mech. He pivoted right, seeking the source of fire, and  
saw infantry movingdvough She shadows a hundred meters away.  
Bringing up the Martell medium laser mounted on his right arm,  
he footed a burst of coherent light at his attackers. A couple then- 
range missiles, probably from marbportable launchers, streaked  
out of the darkness. One exploded against his right shoulder, but  
without Inflkting much damage.
'Ernie?' he called, moving quickly to his left. 'Let's wreck  
those two.-
-Copy that,'
Carlyle turned his autocannon on the Whiboorth, an old and  
uncommon BattleMech he privately lumped In with a general  
subgroup he thought of as "DrekMechs." Whittles were slow and  
cumbersome, poorly armored and poorly armed, with a badly  
designed leg actuator system that left them prone to breakdown.  
The destruction of the Whitworth factory on Dieron during the  
Amads conflict meant no more were being built. This one had  
likely been passed down within some warrior family or other. It  
was painted black with red trim, and something about that tugged  
at the back of Carlyie's mind. The paint was scratched and scoured  
In many places. The 'Mech had been through a few wars.  
Carlyle decided to put It out of its misery with a stream of  
autocannon fire, pounding at It with a long volley. The rapidly

਍﻿  ofdetonations of whi, flame sent massive. whirling chunks 
  pr rm., spinning across the compound as he peeled open the 
  enemy Mech's torso with his high-speed cannon. then but
  Into Me internal structure with his lasr. Portions of Me gent, 
  soucture sagged and twisted. then toppled. taking the savaged 
  Whlturorth wIM it Ina smoking pile of wreckage.
    Hauptman. meanwhile. focused on the eiember. a decent 
  enough light ifirlech armed with a particle prokector cannon and 
  Mork-range missiles. More MOM were streaking In from the infan- 
  try posidon to the right. Carlyle turned his autocannon on Mem 
  while Hauptman finished off the Panther.
   Damn It. where ore the test of the 'Macias? The only answer 
  Carlyle could arrive at was Rowe, the planetary capital six hundred 
  kilometers to Me east.
   But something didn't feel right. Using his infrared feed, he 
  carefully scanned the Interior of the compound. He could see the 
  Infantry uattering, fleeing the barrage of heavy firepower. Close 
  by. he saw the heat flares of the two dying 'Meehs. The rest of the 
  compound appeared deserted, and that wasn't right either.
   Carlyle stepped back outside the compound wall, still 
 scanning. He could se, light and heat signatures marking the 
 town half a kilometer away, and...what Me hell?
   There was a giant heat signature north of town. perhaps half 
 a Hick distant He couldn't tell what It was from here, but it was 
 huge, as big as a large building and it was giving off a hell of a lot  of heat. It was noisy, too. He'd been aware of the sound from the 
 of heat. It was noisy, too. He'd been aware of the sound from the 
 moment he's stepped onto Golanddnas' surface. but It had been 
 more or less masked by the howl of the wind. Now, though, he 
could hear It more clearly; a deep-throated rumble punctuated by 
shrill shrieks drifted across the rocky terrain.
  "Major Colby! Recon."
  "Go ahead?
  Carlyle described what he was seeing, transmitted an 
electronic copy of the heat signature. and added, I'm going to 
check it out."
  'Copy. Yell if you need help."
  Carlyle put his Shadow Hawk in motion, taking several long, 
bounding strides before kicking in his jump jets and launching his 
'Mech Into a low, flat trajectory. The winds and flying bits of Ice 
Clawed at him; the rumble grew louder. He landed, broke into a 
run, then jumped again...then again....

਍﻿T. Whinvordm black and red livery, had mwa:IcemCarly117.e‘us;were pidous. Both it and the Panther orze. least the  
reided by me Maconis combine. Men ..n
Mec'	
faces	
unit here was he hiring
supposed to re gathering a mercer.,"	
•
Pled. horn across Me nearby border
"r'0';was Me Draconis Combine behind this operation in a more
direct and sinister way,
Look. Major: he said over the comm. "I think the Combine  
Is in the smehow.' He told Colby of he suspicions. of he burls:
'Meth. and Me Whitworts black-and-red color scheme.
"Mat doesn't ma. sense. They wouldn't launch a coo-bonky
raid this deep into Lyran tetrito,"
'Maybe it's not a raid."
"Invasion? There's not a lot here that's worth Invading..
That we know of, sir. I'm almost there. Give me five minutes'  
You've got them. Rendezvous at the depot."
Eighty meters to go now. A final leap, lump lets shrieking._
Carlyle came down In an open field strewn with white,  
crystalline rocks. What is thaf...quorte He thought so. He could see  
the source of the giant heat plumes now...an enormous. mobile  
machine five stories tall and fifty meters long, like a ponderous,  
segmented worm grinding slowly through rock and dirt. The sound  
assaulted him, an ongoing explosion that made Carlyle's Shadow  
Hawk tremble. The Vickers Mining logo showed on the machine's  
work-worn flank. The thing was old...probably a relic of the Star  
League era. An MMR unit, a mobile mining refinery....
The leading edge of the thing, half-burled In the ground,  
chewed its ponderous way forward at the blistering pace of  
several meters per hour, pulling rock into Its maw by the ton and  
pulverizing it between massive, slow-turning crushers. Crushed  
rock was then fed by conveyers to fusion-driven furnaces, then  
routed through extractors that separated pure metal from dross.  
Cooling slag was discarded from the rear, plied up like Immense  
worm castings and leaving a bizarre and desolate wasteland of  
scarred and tortured earth in its wake. A pressurized control cabin  
and crew quarters were located high up on the dorsal surface,  
but the monstrous machine could operate robotically. Carlyle
wondered if this one had a crew. No cabin lights; It was probably  
on automatic.

਍﻿          Movement to the right caught cadyies attention and he 
       pivoted, bringing his ...cannon to bear.
          A Dragon-
          -major!' he shouted. wondering it Colby could hear him 
       above the thunder. "Confirmed! it's a Kurna opl.
          'Haut no you knot,
          The Dragon opened up with Its Imperator, autocannon, 
       sending a stream of high-explosive shells slamming into Carlyle's 
       left arm and side.
          -Dragon/- Carlyle yelled, twisting his 'Moon clear. taking
     fir,
          The monster massed sixty to and mooed a red-and-black 
   paint scheme similar to the wrecked WhIrtuor M. confirming the 
   Combine's Involvement Dragons occasionally were found In the 
   employ of non-Combine forces. but House Kurlta had a nea, 
   monopoly on the squat, ugly things, with so many serving in their 
   line 'Moen units they might as well have been the trademarked 
   combat machine for the Draconls Combine.
       The big question remained. Were these Deathgeld Mech- 
   Warriors recruited from Combine territory? Or were they here as 
   an advance guard for the Draconis Combine, the spearhead of 
   an Invasion? The Combine border with the Lyran Commonwealth 
   was over a hundred light years distant, but it wasn't Impossible 
   that the Kontos were hitting Golandrinas as a prelude to a large- 
   scale assault on House Steiner.
       How to prove that, one way or the other?
       Carlyle triggered his jump jets. soaring left as the enemy 
   'Meth loosed a second autovannon volley. He came down hard; 
   he'd taken damage to his left-side jump jet, and It wasn't firing 
 with full efficiency. The Dragon was already pivoting, raising its left 
 arm which housed a Victory 23R medium laser.
       Carlyle fired his Martell laser, hammering at the enemy 
 'Meth's massive torso. The Dragon staggered back a step, trying 
to avoid that storm of coherent light. Its Telos long-range missile 
system was mounted In a kind of heavy snout protruding from 
Its central torso. Carlyle hoped to cripple that before any Colby's 
Commando 'Mechs came within range.
   The Shadow Hawk and the Dragon were quite closely paired 
with one another in arms and armor, which meant this duel would 
quickly devolve into a slugfest that would leave both machines 
wrecked and helpless. His single advantage lay in his jump jets;

਍﻿     smwan was as fast as Me Shadow Hawk. and lacked his jump 
   me ospabinty, hut. at and weapons loadout were slightly better 







   if Carlyle was going to win, he needed to find a way to heat the


      using his manetwerabifiW


     ca,ryie jumped again. this time coming down squarely behlnd 




   the enemy or He opened up with his autocannon...then saw 



   the raw flare of light as the Drug. fired its rear-facing medium 



   imer.



     Damn/ He'd momentarily forgotten that small design detail] 




   At dose range. the laser pulse hit him squarely in his chest. 



   Continuing to Pre, he stepped to the left slamming round after 



   high-explosive round into Me Dragon's back and flank.



    As the other 'Mech clumsily pivoted In place, Carlyle began 




   to Initiate yet another lump sequence, but killed the command 



  as he glanced at his readouts. The Shadow Hotok's viewscreens 



  were fluctuating, a. another jump—or another direct hit by that 




  backside laser—could have unforeseeable repercussions.




    Adding insult and a great deal of fear to injury, he saw three 



  more 'Mecca emerge from behind the massive machine—a 




  Thunderbolt, a Wolverine, and a second Dragon, all bearing the 




 Draconian Deathgeld colors.




    A full lance of four heavy Deathgeld 'Mech. deliberately 




 hiding their heat signatures behind the mining machine. The 




 only reason to pull a stunt like that would be If they knew Colbys 




 Commandos were on the way. In this frigid nightside environment. 




 a powered-up 'Meth would stand out Ilke a tarantula on an empty 




 dinner plate. pumping geysers of heat Into the atmosphere even 




 while standing still. The Vickers mining refinery provided the 




 perfect cover from which to spring an ambush.




   "Major Colby)" he transmitted. screaming to be sure he could 




 be heard above the racket. "Hold off) Hold off) It's a trap)"




   "We see it, Durant) Pull the hell out of there. Fall back and rejoin
n


                                                                      the unit."
the unit."




   "Not sure that's an option right now," he replied, continuing 



                                                                      to exchange shots with the nearest Dragon. He began retreating. 
to exchange shots with the nearest Dragon. He began retreating. 




                                                                      stepping backward as the Dragon advanced. As Carlyle moved, 
stepping backward as the Dragon advanced. As Carlyle moved, 



                                                                      he triggered the short-range missile launcher mounted on his 
he triggered the short-range missile launcher mounted on his 




                                                                      'Mech's cockpit housing, sending a pair of Holly Derringers 
'Mech's cockpit housing, sending a pair of Holly Derringers 




                                                                      streaking out to slam Into the Dragon's torso. The explosions lit 
streaking out to slam Into the Dragon's torso. The explosions lit 



                                                                      up the dark landscape with a spectacular one-two Rash, sending 
up the dark landscape with a spectacular one-two Rash, sending 




                                                                      chunks of shrapnel hurtling through the night.
chunks of shrapnel hurtling through the night.

਍﻿    Reload-Nei Reload...firel He triggered his laser again as wen. 
  husbanding the shots to avoid building up too much heat. The 
 gmgon appeared to be In trouble. It shambled forward. stumbling 
 a bit. and when It fired its laser at a range of lust thirty meters, It was a clean miss
 was a clean miss
    Then the long-range missiles came streaking ...shirty Holly 
 aMs loosed as a deadly swarm by Natalie BryanrsCd.pult Many 
 missed their intended target. possibly because of the high winds, 
 stoking the ground or the tasseling clIffside of the Vickers MMR 
 close by, but just as many slammed Into the Praconis Thunderbolt. 
 which ponderously turned to face the attack with an DOA volley 
 of Ih own.
   The rest of the company must really have been humping. get 
 heretoquickly.Cadyle maneuvered to keep the first Dragon between 
 him and the rest of the enemy force and continued to retreat.
   Shifting his aim from the damaged Dragon to the massive 
 Deathgeid Thunderbolt Carlyle tagged Its launch rack and left 
 shoulder with his laser. then sent a long stream of explosive shells 
 Into Its torso. The Thunderbolt turned back to him, raising its large 
 gunglow Type-2 laser, but Carlyle fired his lump lets and sailed 
 toward the relative cover of the mining machine, overriding the 
 Shrilling of his heat alarm as he came down with a crunch. The 
 Thunderbolts first shot missed: Its second slashed into the Vickers 
 machine in an explosion of hot plasma and fragments.
   Bryant's second volley struck the Thunderbolt again: Its right 
 arm, bearing the large laser, was blasted from its shoulder. Carlyle 
 stepped out from behind the mining machine and opened fire on 
 the Draconis T-Bolt just as more LII.Ms smashed Into Its back and 
 side. The heavy 'Mech began limping clear of the fight. trailing       smoke from the shredded rule of its shoulder.
smoke from the shredded rule of its shoulder.
  As Carlyies heat warnings shrilled an clam he put two more            bolts of coherent light into the first Dragon, which ground to a        shuddering and furiously smoking halt.
bolts of coherent light into the first Dragon, which ground to a        shuddering and furiously smoking halt.
shuddering and furiously smoking halt.
  And then the rest of Colby's Commandos swarmed onto the               battlefield. hammering at the damaged Thunderbolt, the second           Dragon, and the Wolverine. Colby's 6M Wolverine descended               on blazing lump jets and closed with the enemy's Wolverine, a           flightless 6K. Both variant machines had had their original au-         tocannon swapped out for large lasers, and for a dazzlingly lit         moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
battlefield. hammering at the damaged Thunderbolt, the second           Dragon, and the Wolverine. Colby's 6M Wolverine descended               on blazing lump jets and closed with the enemy's Wolverine, a           flightless 6K. Both variant machines had had their original au-         tocannon swapped out for large lasers, and for a dazzlingly lit         moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
Dragon, and the Wolverine. Colby's 6M Wolverine descended               on blazing lump jets and closed with the enemy's Wolverine, a           flightless 6K. Both variant machines had had their original au-         tocannon swapped out for large lasers, and for a dazzlingly lit         moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
on blazing lump jets and closed with the enemy's Wolverine, a           flightless 6K. Both variant machines had had their original au-         tocannon swapped out for large lasers, and for a dazzlingly lit         moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
flightless 6K. Both variant machines had had their original au-         tocannon swapped out for large lasers, and for a dazzlingly lit         moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
tocannon swapped out for large lasers, and for a dazzlingly lit         moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
moment the two slashed at one another at a range of only a              few meters.
few meters.

਍﻿    The Dragon fumed its autocannon on Colby's womenne as it 
   exchanged fire with its opposite number. !flDlcdng savage run, 
   on Colby's machine, but then Hauptman s Shadow Hauck opened 
   up on It with autocannon and laser fire. The Deathgeld Worm.. 
   closed with Colby. grappling with Me other Mech.
    pe Salvo's Commando. all eyenty-live tons of it slammed into 
   the far more massive BB-ton Wolverine, knocking It sideway, acid    clear of Colby's 'Mech.
   clear of Colby's 'Mech.
    "Present for yo, Mealierhe yelled over his comm.
   The heavier 'Meth turned, raising Its large laser to fry The 
   imperdnem Cornmondo...and took a full double-flight of LAM, 
   from Bryan's Gatopult. the explosions stroblng and flashIngacroye  Its back and side in a perfecdy coordinated strike.
  Its back and side in a perfecdy coordinated strike.
   'Good one. Diesel!" Natalie Bryant yelled back.
   Carlyle grinned and pumped his 'Meth's list In the air, 'Yeah'. 
  It looked like those two could work closely together when tt 
 counted.
   The enemy, badly outnumbered now, was having trouble 
 facing Colby's Commandos, which were attacking from three 
 sides.
   Crippled by Bryant'S broadside, the enemy Wolverine turned 
 and began limping dear of the skirmish. followed by the surviving 
 Dragon. both of them harried from the rear by De Salve's Commando 
 and Hernandez's and Zeller's much smaller Locusts.
   The Deathgeld Thunderbolt had stopped moving.
   And so had Colby's Woloerine.



                                                                    Union-class Dropship Ragamuffin                                     Gala drinas                                                         Lyran Commonwealth                                                  6 April 2990
Union-class Dropship Ragamuffin                                     Gala drinas                                                         Lyran Commonwealth                                                  6 April 2990
Gala drinas                                                         Lyran Commonwealth                                                  6 April 2990
Lyran Commonwealth                                                  6 April 2990
6 April 2990
                                                                    "We lost; a badly wounded Colby said to Durant and the others       some hours later. "We beat them...but we lost:
"We lost; a badly wounded Colby said to Durant and the others       some hours later. "We beat them...but we lost:
some hours later. "We beat them...but we lost:
  They'd made it back to the DropShip, and now stood in Its         sickbay. Swathed in bandages, Colby had been seriously bowed.       The enemy Wolverine's large laser had partially burned through his  cockpit, though the mere unit's leader had ejected before it had    killed hint. He would be out of commission for quite a while, though
sickbay. Swathed in bandages, Colby had been seriously bowed.       The enemy Wolverine's large laser had partially burned through his  cockpit, though the mere unit's leader had ejected before it had    killed hint. He would be out of commission for quite a while, though
The enemy Wolverine's large laser had partially burned through his  cockpit, though the mere unit's leader had ejected before it had    killed hint. He would be out of commission for quite a while, though
cockpit, though the mere unit's leader had ejected before it had    killed hint. He would be out of commission for quite a while, though
killed hint. He would be out of commission for quite a while, though

਍﻿    "How do You figure that. Boss?" De Salve asked. 'We sent
  lbastards hotfooting out of Dodge! Killed four of thelr'hileNs 
  for one of ours, and hurt two more pretty barn We even have a 
  dead Thunderboff we can use for parts for Pryods 'Afiechl Sounds 
  OM a win mei"
    "yeahto; Hauptman said, "but we got here too late to stop the 

 rest from marching on Rowe. Our mission. remember,"
    "That Dragon pilot we captured crowed about it." Colby sold. 
 shaking his head. They'd picked the pilot up on the battlefield 
 after the fight—Lieutenant Senichi Fliramalm, a Combine mere 
 "According to him, there are six more tinechs out there stomping 

 Rowe flat right nowt"
    "Seems to me." Carlyle said slowly, "our missiondidn't have a 

 chance to begin with. We were being set up to take a fall."
    -By who," Bryant asked. "Suartosr

    "Probably that slimy bastard Reid; Colby said He shifted on 
 his sickbay cot, grimacing despite the painkillers. 'I'd be willing to  bet he's working for the Combine:
 bet he's working for the Combine:
    "So why did he hire us?' Bryant asked.
    "Because Suartos told him to: Carlyle said. 'But he also made 
 sure to warn Me Deathgelds."
    "Might have been public relations: Bryant suggested. "They 

 could have claimed we were raiders threatening the planet, and 
 they destroyed us."
    "But what Is it they want on this rock anyway?" Hauptman 
 asked. 'The Vickers mining claim?'
    Carlyle turned to a corner of the sickbay where he'd left a 

small duffle bag. He lifted it with some difficulty hefted it, then 
reached inside.
   The heavy bar of soft, smooth metal he produced gleamed In 

the bright lights.
  "Gold?" De Salva asked.

  'Exactly. After the fight. I got to thinking that the Deathgeld 

wasn't Just using that Vickers MMR for cover. They were protecting 

it. My guess is that the Draconls Combine got wind of a gold strike 

here, and sent the Deathgeld in to grab it. So I ripped open the 

miner's side and poked around inside." He held up both hands 

and flexed them. 1 like a 'Mech with hands! Anyway. I found a 

locked vault with walls that tore open ilke cardboard. I counted 

five hundred of these bricks Inside. Each one masses a standard 

12.4 kilos. ComStar's current exchange rate will be about half a 
million C-bills each."

਍﻿    -  hundred fifty million C-hills." De Salve said, his volca



  near,ddsper as he did the math.

               'So mars...?


    Co.?, .35..ne'.

    The peamgeids pay. Carlyle said, nodding at the gleaming



  bat-mod likely, they'd take a percentage. and ship the rest hack 


  to the Combine. Ideathgeld..rknow I think the Combine put them 



  together lust to make this raid. 'Deathgeld' could stand for 'Death 


  dad'you now?The strike here looks rich enough to fund all sod, 



  dmonmine operations out this way without having to explain whet 
  they lust CornStat But the Important thing Is...."






    .We lust grabbed the Deathgeld's payroll!' Colby exclaimed. 


    -Right When Me rest of them hear about this—and TB bet th, 



  have already from the survivors of their garrison here In Trent—i



  don't Mink they'll bother with Rowe."


   'uppers; Colby said "They'll head back this way breathing



Pre. That might not be so good for us...."


   -Bywhichdmewe'll beonourwaYoutRYRM,A"CerlYleShrugged. 



"Or we hide the gold. sit dght. and negotiate. Your call, Skipper." 


   'You think they'll be willing to talk?" Bryant asked.



   "Of course. After all..." Colby grinned. "It's the goys with the 



gold who make the rules...."

